One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
It's all right! It's time to move on
‫لا بأس! هيا نمضي قُدمًا‬
The sun shines always in our hearts
‫فالشمس تُدفئ قلوبنا دومًا‬
Hand in hand, we convey our power
‫قوةٌ تعبر بين أيادينا المتشابكة‬
And make our wishes come true
‫هيا نُحقق أمنياتنا‬
Combining our strengths, we'll crest these surging seas
‫لنركب الأمواج العاتية بالعمل معًا‬
Hurry toward the thrill of danger— Let the adventure begin!
‫لنسرع إلى التشويق... ها هي إشارة البداية‬
Now's the time to set sail; raise the anchor
‫قد حان وقتُ الإبحار، فلنرفع المرساة‬
Off to the seas of adventure, through rainbow-colored winds
‫عبر الريح الملونة بألوان الطيف نخترق صوبَ بحرِ المغامرة‬
Our journey's fraught with injury
‫لن تسلم رحلتنا من الإصابات‬
But what we cherish most is right at our side
‫لكن ما نعتز به سيكون هناك‬
And if you get into a jam
‫وإن وقعت في مأزق‬
I'll always be there to protect you
‫ستجدني معك لأحميك‬
It's all right! It's time to move on
‫لا بأس هيا نمضي قُدمًا‬
The sun shines always in our hearts
‫فالشمس تُدفئ قلوبنا دومًا‬
Shoulder to shoulder, we face all coming storms
‫حتى إن عصفت عاصفة سنعانق بعضنا‬
And look to the future for the light of hope
‫ونوجه ناظرنا نحو الضوء البعيد‬
If we gather up the pieces of our dreams
‫إن جمعنا شظايا أحلامنا‬
They'll make a chart leading to tomorrow
‫سنُشكل خريطةً تقودنا إلى الغد‬
We come together under the same Jolly Roger
‫لذا لنُحقق أمنياتنا‬
And make our wishes come true; together, we are...
‫علمٌ واحد يجمعنا، نحن واحد‬
The City of Water, Water Seven
‫مدينة الماء، ووتر سيفن‬
Luffy and Robin needed to recover, so the Going Merry remained anchored off the uninhabited island for four days.
‫من أجل حصول لوفي وروبين على‬ ‫بعض الرّاحة، رست الغوينغ ميري‬
After that, we set sail, and now this is the third morning since we resumed our voyage.
‫بعد ذلك، أبحرنا‬
Today's weather is a gorgeous mix of spring...
‫إنّه يوم جميل، الرّبيع جزئي...‬
and occasional bouts of summer.
‫مع نوبات صيفيّة من حين لآخر‬
What a beautiful day!
‫يا له من يومٍ جميل‬
Nami my sweet!
‫نامي-سان‬
I made pomme paille. Mademoiselle, if you would...
‫أعددتُ باي البطاطا يا آنستي، تفضّلي...‬
Mmm, it's delicious!
‫إنّها لذيذة‬
I'm overjoyed!
‫أنا سعيد‬
Keep it down! I'm trying to sleep!
‫اخرس أيّها النّذل، إنّك تُقلق نومي‬
Yeah, yeah... Sorry about that, cactus head.
‫أجل، أجل، متأسّفين على ذلك يا رأس الصّبّار‬
What'd you say, dartboard brows?!
‫ماذا قلت يا وجه لوحة السِّهام؟‬
Dar– Did I hear you right, you bastard?!
‫لوحـ... ماذا قلت أيّها الوغد؟‬
Dartboard brows.
‫حواجب السّهام‬
Luffy! Yeah! Luffy! All right!
‫لوفي، أجل، لوفي، مرحى‬
Luffy! Yeah! Luffy!
‫لوفي، أجل، لوفي‬
Finally!
‫أخيرًا‬
Luffy!
‫لوفي‬
This is my frozen-self reenactment.
‫أنا أقلّد نفسي المجمّدة‬
The heck...? I can't believe he's doing that after he got frozen and almost died.
‫يا إلهي... لا أصدّق أنّه يفعل ذلك بعد‬ ‫أن جُمّد وكان على شفا حفرة من الموت‬
Was it close?
‫هل قمتُ بعمل جيّد؟‬
You nailed it! That was exactly it, Luffy!
‫فعلت، بدوت كذلك تمامًا يا لوفي‬
Clean that up good, okay, Luffy?!
‫نظّف ذلك جيّدًا، مفهوم يا لوفي؟‬
Hm...? Oh! What're you eating, Nami?
‫ماذا؟ ماذا تأكلين يا نامي؟‬
It's paille, a potato dish.
‫إنّه طبق باي البطاطا‬
Potato, huh? I'm hungry too. Hey, Sanji!
‫بطاطا؟ أنا جائع أيضًا يا سانجي‬
Just how much sleep do you need anyway?!
‫كم تحتاج من النّوم لترضى؟‬
How much sleep I "need" is my business! Let's settle this!
‫ذلك يخصّني أنا، سأواجهك إن كنت تريد القتال‬
They said this is called paille. It's good!
‫يقال أنّه يدعى باي، إنّه لذيذ‬
What's paille?
‫ما معنى باي؟‬
It's the tail meat of a huge monster named Paille.
‫إنّه لحم ذيل وحش ضخم يدعى باي‬
I slew it, though. It was at least a hundred meters tall.
‫لقد قتلته، كان طوله 100 متر على الأقل‬
A hundred meters?! That's amazing, Usopp!
‫مئة متر؟ هذا مذهل يا أوسوبّ‬
Yeah, and I did it all before breakfast.
‫كان ذلك سهلًا، قضيتُ عليه قبل الإفطار‬
What? You got up early and killed it?
‫ماذا؟ استيقظتَ باكرًا وقتلته؟‬
Chopper, say my name.
‫تشوبّر، ردّد اسمي‬
What? That's, of course, C-Captain...
‫ماذا؟ ذلك... بالطّبع يا قـ-قبطان...‬
That's right! My name is Captain... Usopp–
‫صحيح، هذا هو اسمي... القبطان... أوسوبّ‬
Robin!
‫روبين‬
Hey! Robin my love!
‫مرحى، روبين-تشان‬
How are you feeling? Are you chilly?
‫كيف حالك؟ هل تشعرين بالبرد؟‬
I'm feeling a lot better all thanks to an amazing doctor.
‫أنا أشعر بتحسّن كبير،‬ ‫شكرًا لك يا طبيبي الممتاز‬
Oh, being called an amazing doctor won't make me feel happy or anything, you jerk.
‫دعوتي بالطّبيب الممتاز لن يجعلني‬ ‫سعيدًا أيّتها الغبيّة‬
He sure does look happy.
‫يبدو سعيدًا بالفعل‬
Yeah.
‫نعم‬
Take it easy, Robin.
‫هوّني على نفسك يا روبين‬
Don't feel pressured just because Luffy is up and about after experiencing the same thing.
‫قد تنزعجين عندما ترين لوفي بأفضل حال‬
It's okay to take your time and rest.
‫لكن بإمكانك أخذ وقتك والاستراحة‬
– Yay! – That wasn't a compliement!
‫مرحى -‬ ‫لم يكن إطراءً -‬
Robin! Shall I make something to warm you up?
‫روبين-تشان، هل أعدّ لك شيئًا يُدفئ جسدك؟‬
How's your appetite?
‫هل شهيّتك مفتوحة؟‬
Well...
‫إذًا... هلّي بكوب من القهوة؟‬
Absolutely! It'll be my pleasure!
‫حاضر، بكلّ سرور‬
What's that?
‫ما ذلك؟‬
Anyway, this paille thing is so good that we can't stop eating it.
‫على أيّ حال، هذا الشّيء الّذي يدعى باي‬ ‫لذيذ جدًّا ولا نستطيع مقاومته، صحيح؟‬
Yeah, it's yummy!
‫نعم، إنّه لذيذ‬
How much would we make if we sold this?
‫بالمناسبة، ألا تظنّان أنّنا نستطيع‬ ‫درّ بعض المال إن بعنا هذا؟‬
Hey, Luffy!
‫يا لوفي‬
A f-f-frog is doing the front crawl!
‫ثمّة ضـ-ضفدع يقوم بالسّباحة الحرّة‬
It went to your side, so take a look!
‫سبح إلى جهتكم، لذا ألقوا نظرة‬
Is that true?
‫أهذا صحيح؟‬
A frog...? Could it be that frog?
‫ضفدع... أيعقل أن يكون ذلك الضّفدع؟‬
Hey, Luffy, are you seriously taking stock in what that dumb admiral said?
‫يا لوفي، هل تأخذ ما قاله ذلك‬ ‫الأميرال الغبيّ محمل الجدّ؟‬
For starters, a frog could never do the–
‫أساسًا، يستحيل أن يقوم ضفدع‬ ‫بالسّباحة الحـ... بلى‬
It's doing it! A-A frog is doing the front crawl!
‫إنه كذلك‬
Let's follow it, guys!
‫سنتبعه‬
– Aye!
‫أجل‬
Furl the sail! Stand by the oars! Turn the ship to two o'clock!
‫افردوا الأشرعة وخذوا المجاديف،‬ ‫أديروا السّفينة باتّجاه السّاعة الثّانية‬
– Aye!
‫حاضر -‬ ‫بسرعة -‬
I can't explain it, but I can't fight the urge to go after it!
‫لا أدري لماذا، لكن أشعر أنّنا يجب أن نلاحقه‬
Sorry to keep you waiting, mademoiselles.
‫آسف على التّأخّر يا آنستاي‬
What the...?
‫ما الّذي...‬
What?! What happened?!
‫ماذا؟ ما الّذي حدث؟‬
It feels like the ship changed course.
‫يبدو أنّ السّفينة غيّرت مسارها‬
Hey, you guys! Who said you could change course without consulting me?!
‫أنتم، لماذا غيّرتم المسار دون استشارتي؟‬
Hey, Nami, you've got to hear this!
‫عليك سماع هذا يا نامي‬
We found a huge frog with scars all over its body!
‫وجدنا ضفدعًا ضخمًا مكلّلًا بالنّدوب‬
The plan's to roast it whole and eat it!
‫سنحمّصه كلّه ونأكله بكلّ تأكيد‬
– You're gonna eat it?!
‫ستأكله؟‬
Hey, you're right.
‫كلامك صحيح...‬
Hm? Is that a lighthouse?
‫ماذا؟ أتلك منارة؟‬
Why is there a lighthouse all the way out here? I wonder if someone's there...
‫ما الّذي تفعله منارة في مكان كذاك؟‬ ‫أتساءل إن كان أحدهم هناك...‬
Wh-What do you see? Is it an island?
‫مـ-ما الأمر؟ هل ترين جزيرة؟‬
No, it's a lighthouse. Log poses shouldn't point to places like these.
‫كلّا، هنالك منارة، ما كانت البوصلة‬ ‫المسجّلة لتشير إلى مكان كذاك‬
And the frog? Tell us the direction the frog went!
‫ماذا عن الضّفدع؟ أخبرينا بالاتّجاه‬ ‫الّذي سبح إليه الضّفدع‬
Not a chance!
‫إطلاقًا‬
Not a chance! The frog is headed to the lighthouse.
‫الضفدع متّجه إلى المنارة‬
the slime using white wine,
‫من أجل طبخ الضّفادع، يجب إزال المادّة‬ ‫اللّزجة أوّلًا باستعمال النّبيذ الأبيض‬
and then dredge them in flour and fry them crisp.
‫ثمّ نضع عليها الدّقيق ونقليها حتّى تتقرمش‬
in flour and fry them crisp. Hey, Sanji!
‫مهلًا يا سانجي-كن‬
Hey, Sanji! If our captain says we're going, what choice do we have but to go?
‫إن قرّر قبطاننا أن نذهب، هل نملك خيارًا آخر؟‬
Robin... If our captain says we're going, what choice do we have but to go?
‫روبين...‬
All right! Full speed ahead!
‫حسنًا، إلى الأمام بأقصى سرعة‬
– Aye!
‫أجل‬
What's with the solidarity?!
‫ما هذا التّآلف فجأةً؟‬
– Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
‫هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا‬
It's flying!
‫لقد حلّق‬
Don't let it get away! Move ahead of it and block its course!
‫لا تدعوه يهرب، سنسبقه ثمّ نعترض طريقه‬
– Heave-ho! Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
‫هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا، هيّا بنا‬
We ran aground on something!
‫اصطدمنا باليابسة أو ما شابه‬
Ah, Nami, Robin, are you two okay?
‫نامي-سان، روبين-تشان، هل أنتما بخير؟‬
Yeah, somehow...
‫نعم، بطريقةٍ ما...‬
I'm okay.
‫أنا بخير‬
Thank goodness.
‫جيّد...‬
What? What's that sound?
‫ماذا؟ ما هذا الصوت؟‬
What? What's going on?
‫ماذا؟ ما الّذي يجري؟‬
Is this...? Don't tell me...
‫أهذا...؟ لا يعقل...‬
Why...? In a place like this...?!
‫لماذا... في مكان كهذا...؟‬
Ow, ow, ow!
‫هذا مؤلم، مؤلم، مؤلم...‬
Go back! Go back! Rotate 180 degrees!
‫عودوا، عودوا، أديروا السّفينة 180 درجة‬
What the hell is this?!
‫ما ذلك بالضبط؟‬
Wh-Wh-What in the world is this hulking piece of iron?!
‫مـ-ما هذه الكتلة الحديديّة؟‬
A ship?
‫سفينة؟‬
Impossible! Something shaped like this isn't seaworthy!
‫كلّا، لا يمكن لشيءٍ بهذا الشّكل‬ ‫أن يسافر على البحر‬
Hey, frog! Run! What're you doing?!
‫أيّها الضّفدع اهرب، ما الّذي تفعله؟‬
Ah! It got run over!
‫مصيبة، لقد اصطدم به‬
The ship was puffing out smoke!
‫كانت السّفينة تنفث الدّخان‬
Pirates...?
‫قراصنة...؟‬
Grandma! Grandma! Pirates are here!
‫جدّتي، جدّتي، أتى قراصنة‬
What?! Is that so, Chimney?!
‫ماذا؟ أهذا صحيح يا تشيمني؟‬
Okay then, bring the transponder snail to me!
‫حسنًا إذًا، أحضري لي حلزون الاتّصال‬
Okay!
‫حسنًا‬
This is a problem. Someone came out of the building.
‫هذه مشكلة، خرجت امرأة من المبنى‬
They're gonna call for help.
‫وستستدعي المساعدة‬
Here it is, Grandma!
‫تفضّلي يا جدّتي‬
Um... Hello?
‫مرحبًا؟‬
Let's see... What was it? I forgot.
‫لنرَ... ماذا كنت سأقول؟ نسيت‬
She's wasted?!
‫إنّها ثملة إذًا؟‬
Oh? Paille, huh? It goes good with booze.
‫ماذا؟ باي؟ يتماشى مذاقه جيّدًا مع الكحول‬
Whoa! This is tasty!
‫مذهل، إنّه لذيذ‬
I'm Chimney. This is our cat, Gonbe,
‫أنا تشيمني وهذا قطّنا غونبي...‬
Chimney Kokoro's Grandchild
‫تشيمني‬ ‫حفيدة كوكورو‬
Gonbe A Cat (Actually a Rabbit)
‫غونبي‬ ‫قط(في الواقع أرنب)‬
and Grandma Kokoro.
‫وجدّتي كوكورو‬
Stationmaster Kokoro Shift Station
‫رئيسة المحطة‬ ‫كوكورو‬
You guys aren't train robbers, are you?
‫لستم لصوص القطار، أليس كذلك؟‬
I'm Luffy. I'm the man who'll be King of the Pirates.
‫أنا لوفي، أنا الرّجل الّذي سيصير ملك القراصنة‬
Really?!
‫حقًّا؟ -‬ ‫نعم -‬
What a funny guy.
‫يا له من شخصٍ طريف‬
Say, Chimney, that thing is a steamship, right?
‫أخبريني يا تشيمني، ذلك الشّيء باخرة، صحيح؟‬
But with a shape like that, there's no way it could ever sail.
‫لكن لا يفترض أن تستطيع‬ ‫التّرحال مع شكلٍ كذاك‬
Never seen nothin' like it, huh?
‫لم تروا شيئًا كذلك من قبل، أليس كذلك؟‬
This is the only place in the world it exists.
‫حتّى إن بحثتم في العالم بأكمله‬ ‫لن تجدوه إلّا في هذا المكان‬
It's a sea train called the Puffing Tom.
‫إنّه قطار بحري يُدعى "توم النّافث"‬
Puffing Tom?
‫توم النّافث؟‬
A steam engine turns the paddle wheels as it rides the sea railway.
‫يدير محرّكٌ بخاريٌّ عجلاتِ التّدوير‬ ‫ويسير على السكّة الحديديّة البحريّة‬
Railway?
‫سكّة حديديّة؟‬
That's right. It floats just below the water's surface.
‫نعم، إنّها ممتدّة تحت سطح البحر قليلًا‬
The train travels the same route every day, taking passengers from one island to another.
‫يرتحل القطار من خلال نفس الطريق كلّ يوم‬
It also hauls ships and delivers mail.
‫كما أنّه يحمل السّفن والبريد‬
She's right. There really is a railway.
‫معها حقّ، ثمّة سكّة حديديّة فعلًا‬
Yup! There's both a signal and a partition.
‫هذا صحيح، ثمّة إشارة وحاجز‬
It's dangerous to cross the barrier!
‫من الخطير دخولها هكذا‬
Dangerous or not, that guy wouldn't understand, right?
‫حتّى إن كان خطيرًا، ما كان ذلك‬ ‫الشخص ليعرف، صحيح؟‬
It wasn't nice to send him flying. We were chasing him, you know.
‫لم يكن من الجميل دهسه فقد كنّا نلاحقه‬
By "that guy," do you mean Yokozuna?
‫ماذا؟ أتقصد بـ"ذلك الشّخص" يوكوزونا؟‬
Yep, that front-crawl frog.
‫نعم، ضفدع السّباحة الحرّة ذاك‬
Yokozuna wouldn't die from that.
‫ما كان يوكوزونا ليموت إثر ذلك‬
He's the source of all our headaches here at Shift Station.
‫إنّه أصل كلّ مشكلاتنا في محطّة التّحويل هذه‬
He loves testing his strength by trying to defeat the sea train.
‫يهوى تحدّيات القوّة ودائمًا ما‬ ‫يحاول هزيمة القطار البحري‬
He'll be back.
‫سيأتي ثانيةً‬
Testing his strength? Oh! That's why he stood his ground, huh?
‫تحدّيات القوّة؟ فهمت... لهذا لم يبتعد إذًا؟‬
He's sure got guts.
‫إنّه جريء بحقّ‬
Give me a break! He's a royal pain!
‫إليك عنّي، لدينا مشكلات‬
The grill also keeps getting broken!
‫كُسر حامي السّكّة العديد من المرّات أيضًا‬
Every time he shows up, the passengers freak out!
‫إنّه يتسبّب بالمشكلات للرّكّاب في كلّ مرّة يظهر‬
So that's what he's doing...
‫فهمت...‬
Okay, then! I won't eat him!
‫حسنًا إذًا، لن آكله‬
I can't eat a fighter!
‫لن آكل مقاتلًا‬
Wanting to eat him was your first mistake!
‫ما كان يجب أن تفكّر‬ ‫في أكل ضفدع من الأساس‬
So, you guys headed somewhere?
‫إلى أين تودّون الذّهاب إذًا؟‬
If you're gonna take the sea train from here, there's:
‫إن كنتم ستستقلّون القطار البحري من هنا...‬
St. Poplar, Town of the Spring Queen... Pucci, the Gourmet Town...
‫بلدة ملكة الرّبيع، القدّيس بوبلار...‬ ‫بلدة الذّوّاقة، بوتشي...‬
and San Faldo, the Carnival Town!
‫وبلدة الكرنفال، سان فالدو...‬ ‫كلّها أماكن ممتعة‬
If you work for the government, you'd take a separate, special train.
‫وإن كنتم تعملون مع الحكومة‬ ‫فهنالك قطار خاص ومنفصل‬
Okay, we'll pick the Gourmet Town.
‫سنختار بلدة الذّوّاقة إذًا‬
No, we won't!
‫بالطّبع لا‬
Since we've got our own ship, we won't need the train.
‫بما أنّنا نملك سفينتنا، لن نستقلّ القطار‬
We can follow our log.
‫سنتبع البوصلة فحسب‬
Oh? Where's it pointing?
‫ماذا؟ إلى أين تشير؟‬
Due east from here.
‫شرقًا من هنا‬
So I see... That would be none other than Water Seven.
‫فهمت، لا بدّ أنّها تشير لووتر سيفن إذًا‬
The train you saw earlier came from that island's Blue Station.
‫القطار الّذي رأيتموه سابقًا أتى‬ ‫من المحطّة الزرقاء لتلك الجزيرة‬
It's called the City of Water. It's a real nice place.
‫تُدعى بـ"مدينة الماء". وهي مكان جميل‬
What's more, the city is known far and wide for its shipbuilding industry.
‫قبل كلّ شيء، إنّها مدينة صنعت لنفسها‬ ‫اسمًا من خلال السفانة‬
Their tech is the best in the world!
‫تقنيّتهم هي الأولى في العالم‬
Even the World Government favors the ships built there! Amazing, right?
‫والسّفن الّتي يبنونها تحظى بتفضيل‬ ‫حكومة العالم، أليس ذلك رائعًا؟‬
Then... they've got some awesome shipwrights, right?!
‫فهمت... لا بدّ أنّ فيها بعض‬ ‫السفانين مذهلين إذًا، صحيح؟‬
Not just "some"! Only the world's best shipwrights hang out there!
‫ليس "البعض" فحسب، بل هي منتدى‬ ‫لأفضل السفانين في العالم‬
Usopp!
‫أوسوبّ‬
Yeah!
‫أجل‬
Alright! I've decided!
‫حسنًا، قُضي الأمر‬
We'll go and get a shipwright to join us for sure!
‫سنذهب إلى هناك ونضمّ سفّانًا‬ ‫إلى طاقمنا بالتّأكيد‬
Oh, is that right? Then hold on a sec.
‫هكذا إذًا؟ أمهلني لحظة إذًا‬
Up I go!
‫ها أنا ذي‬
What's she up to?
‫ما الأمر؟‬
Beats me.
‫لا أدري‬
Well, then... Here's a basic map of the island and a letter of introduction.
‫حسنًا... هذه خريطة بسيطة‬ ‫للجزيرة ورسالة مرجعيّة‬
Hand this to a guy named Iceburg and ask him to fix up your ship real good.
‫أعطوا هذه لشخص يدعى أيسبرغ واطلبوا‬ ‫منه أن يصلح سفينتكم على أتمّ وجه‬
Water Seven is a big place. Don't get lost.
‫ووتر سيفن مكان كبير، لا تتوهوا‬
You have a heart of gold, Miss Kokoro! You're so kind!
‫كوكورو-سان، لديك قلب كبير!‬ ‫يا لك من شخص لطيف!‬
In a bit, we're gonna go back to Water Seven too.
‫سوف نعود إلى ووتر سيفن قريبًا أيضًا‬
Oh, true! If we meet again, first round's on me at my favorite bar.
‫نعم، إن التقينا ثانيةً، سأدعوكم‬ ‫للشّراب في حانتي المفضّلة‬
Okay! I hope we see you guys again!
‫حسنًا، آمل أن نلتقي بكما ثانيةً‬
At Water Seven, it'll take about a week for the log to register, so kick back and relax.
‫سيستغرق تسجيل البوصلة نحو أسبوع‬ ‫في ووتر سيفن فلا داعي للعجلة‬
Yeah! Thanks!
‫أجل، شكرًا‬
All right, guys! Get ready to set sail!
‫حسنًا يا رفاق، استعدّوا للإبحار‬
– Yeah!
‫أجل -‬ ‫حسنًا، لنذهب -‬
Thanks for all your help, Miss Kokoro and Chimney!
‫شكرًا على المساعدة يا كوكورو-سان و تشيمني‬
Be careful!
‫توخّوا الحذر‬
Watch out for the government people!
‫احذروا من أتباع البحريّة‬
Yahoo! Let's go!
‫مرحى، هيّا بنا إلى مدينة اللّحم‬
Were you even listening?
‫هل كنت تنصت حتّى؟‬
Mmm. What a nice breeze!
‫يا لها من رياح لطيفة‬
Maybe we'll reach the City of Water sooner than expected.
‫قد نستطيع الوصول إلى مدينة‬ ‫الماء أسرع من المتوقّع‬
I hope so.
‫آمل ذلك‬
Luffy, leave scouting out the shipwright to me. I'll find us an incredibly gorgeous woman.
‫يا لوفي دع مهمّة البحث عن سفان لي،‬ ‫سأجد امرأةً فاتنة الجمال‬
Don't be dumb! We need a shipwright!
‫هل أنت غبيّ؟ إنّنا نتحدّث عن سفان‬
It's gotta be a big guy the size of a mountain! Five meters tall!
‫عليه أن يكون رجلًا ضخمًا كالجبل‬ ‫بطول خمسة أمتار‬
But if he's too big, he might not fit on this ship.
‫لكن إن كان ضخمًا جدًّا، لا ندري‬ ‫إن كان سيرتاح على هذه السّفينة‬
All that matters is that he's skilled, right?
‫المهمّ هو أن يكون ماهرًا، صحيح؟‬
The real question is if there's someone crazy enough to want to be on a pirate ship.
‫والمسألة الأهمّ هي ما إن كنّا سنجد أحدًا‬
I can't wait! We're gonna make a new friend!
‫أتطلّع إلى ذلك، سنرحّب بصديق جديد‬
We were lucky to stop at the station first since they drew a map for us.
‫حالفنا الحظّ للتّوقّف في المحطّة‬ ‫أوّلًا، بما أنّهم رسموا خريطة من أجلنا‬
If we go to the place on the map and find that Iceburg guy...
‫إن ذهبنا إلى المكان المُشار إليه‬ ‫في الخريطة وزرنا المدعو أيسبرغ...‬
Around here Water 7
‫هنا‬ ‫ووتر سيفن‬
Oh, okay.
‫فهمت...‬
This tells me nothing!
‫بسيطة جدًّا على أن تُفهم‬
Whoa! This is like Luffy's art.
‫عجبًا، هذا أشبه برسم لوفي‬
Shipwright meters Here. We need to keep an eye out for a guy like this.
‫سفَّان‬ ‫متر‬ ‫إذًا سنبحث جميعًا عن شخص كهذا‬
I'd run if I saw a guy like that.
‫إن صادفت شخصًا مثله، سأهرب‬
Same here. I'd hop on the next ship and hightail it out to sea.
‫نعم، وأنا أيضًا، إن كان لي قارب‬ ‫فسأهرب إلى البحر‬
But a thug like this might chase me into open water like an octopus.
‫لكن يبدو أنّ لهذا الشّخص علاقة بالأخطبوطات‬
What are you guys jabbering about?
‫ما الّذي تثرثران به؟‬
Come here, guys!
‫حسنًا يا رفاق، تعالوا إلى هنا‬
I'll give you an allowance for the week we're ashore.
‫سأعطيكم مصروفًا من أجل الأسبوع‬ ‫الّذي سنبقى فيه هناك‬
Seriously?! Yay! I'm first!
‫حقًّا؟ مرحى، أنا أوّلًا‬
Whoa! That's generous!
‫هذا سخيّ‬
Hey! Get in line!
‫أنتم، قفوا في الصّفّ‬
You doing okay, Usopp?
‫ما الخطب يا أوسوبّ؟‬
This tinplate patchwork brings back memories of battles and adventure.
‫هذا التّرقيع الصّفيحيّ يعيد لي‬ ‫ذكريات معارك ومغامرات‬
I can't help but gush over the thought of her upcoming repairs.
‫تغمرني مشاعر عميقة عندما أفكّر‬ ‫نّها ستُصلح عمّا قريب.‬
I get it, but...
‫فهمت ذلك، لكن...‬
Huh?
‫أثّرت رحلتنا بشكلٍ كبير على الميري‬ ‫ولا سيّما بعد دخولنا إلى الغراند لاين‬
The deck creaks, and the ship's bottom is pretty leaky.
‫يصدر سطح السّفينة صريرًا كما‬ ‫أنّ التّسرّب في أسفل السّفينة سيّئ أيضًا‬
If nothing's done, that'll be it for both the ship and us.
‫إلّم نفعل شيئًا، فسنكون نحن وسفينتنا في خطر‬
Yeah, but we're filthy rich now.
‫نعم، لكنّنا نملك أموالًا طائلة الآن‬
We can make her good as new! And more powerful, too!
‫بإمكاننا أن نصلحها على أتمّ وجه‬ ‫كما يمكننا تعزيزها أيضًا‬
Yeah! More cannons!
‫حسنًا، لنحصل على المزيد من المدافع‬
Also, a bronze statue!
‫إذًا لنحصل على تمثال سفينة برونزيّ أيضًا‬
Hey, is that it?
‫لحظة، أليست تلك المنشودة؟‬
It's the island! We can see the island!
‫الجزيرة، أصبحت الجزيرة على مرآنا‬
Okay, guys! Row!
‫حسنًا يا رفاق، جدّفوا‬
We've got a decent tailwind. We shouldn't waste energy!
‫الرّياح كافية، لا تجعلنا نهدر طاقتنا‬
How wonderful!
‫كم هي عجيبة...‬
It's incredible!
‫مذهلة...‬
Water Seven "The City of Water" Grand Line
‫ووتر سيفن‬ ‫"مدينة الماء"‬ ‫بالغراند لاين‬
What is this place?!
‫ما هذا؟‬
The fountain's enormous!
‫يا لها من نافورة ضخمة‬
Unbelievable! An actual industrial city!
‫مذهلة، إنّها مدينة صناعيّة بحقّ‬
That's why it has the sea train.
‫لا عجب أن يملك هذا المكان قطارًا بحريًّا‬
That must be the station in front.
‫لا بدّ أنّ تلك في المقدّمة هي المحطّة‬
It says "Blue Station."
‫مكتوب عليها المحطّة الزّرقاء‬
I wonder where we dock.
‫أتساءل أين هو المرسى‬
In town somewhere?
‫لا بدّ أنّه في البلدة‬
Hey, you there!
‫يا رفاق‬
Pirates shouldn't openly sail out in front.
‫ليس من الجيّد أن يبحر القراصنة‬ ‫علانيّة في الأمام‬
Go around to the Backstreets!
‫التفّوا من حول الشّوارع الخلفيّة هناك‬
Okay! Thanks!
‫حسنًا، شكرًا‬
Whoa, this is amazing! A city on the water?!
‫عجبًا، هذا مذهل، مدينة في الماء؟‬
Wow! This place is cool! Such a pretty city!
‫مذهل، هذا المكان رائع،‬ ‫يا لها من مدينة جميلة!‬
But the city is flooded. The houses are submerged in the sea.
‫لكنّ المدينة غارقة والبيوت مغمورة في البحر‬
Look again.
‫ليس كذلك، صُمّمت المدينة لتكون قاعدتها غارقة‬
You can see the foundation underneath.
‫انظر للأساس الموجود أسفل المباني‬
Oh, true! The pillars raise the structures!
‫أنت محقّة، بُنيت الأعمدة لتكون أطول‬
I see... That's why it's called the City of Water, huh?
‫فهمت... لهذا تُدعى مدينة الماء إذًا؟‬
Hey, hurry up and dock the ship!
‫هيّا، أسرعوا وأرسوا السّفينة‬
Hey, listen up, you guys! Pirate ships should steer clear of this area!
‫يا رفاق، لا يجب على سفن‬ ‫القراصنة أن تأتي إلى هنا‬
Did you come here to plunder?
‫لِمَ أتيتم إلى هنا؟ لتنهبوا؟‬
No! We wanna get our ship repaired!
‫لا، نريد إصلاح سفينتنا‬
People just up and ask if we're gonna plunder...?
‫هل يسأل النّاس عادةً إن كنّا أتينا لنهبهم؟‬
In that case, there's a cape just ahead, so anchor your ship there for now!
‫إذًا ثمّة رأس في المقدّمة، لذا‬ ‫اُرسوا سفينتكم هناك حاليًّا‬
Okay!
‫عُلم‬
Thanks!
‫شكرًا‬
Again?
‫ثانيةً؟‬
What'd you expect? We're pirates, after all.
‫ما باليد حيلة، صحيح؟ نحن قراصنة في الأخير‬
This spot's okay, right?
‫يجدر أن تكون هذه المنطقة بخير، أليس كذلك؟‬
It sure is bleak though.
‫على أيّ حال، إنّه مكان مملّ‬
All right, then! Furl the sail!
‫حسنًا إذًا، اجمعوا الأشرعة‬
What're you doing?!
‫ما الّذي تفعله؟‬
Nothing! All I did was pull the rope!
‫لا شيء، سحبت الحبل فقط‬
You're kidding me! The Going Merry has gotten this rickety?
‫يا للهول، هل أصبحت الغوينغ ميري‬ ‫متهالكة بهذا القدر؟‬
Anyway, why aren't the people on this island scared of pirates?
‫بالمناسبة، لِمَ لا يخاف أهل‬ ‫هذه الجزيرة من القراصنة؟‬
Pirates probably come here for ships too.
‫ربما لأن القراصنة يعدون من زبائن حوضهم للسفانة‬
Less talking! More fixing!
‫كفاك لغوًا وأصلحها بسرعة‬
Maybe they have sentries strong enough to deal with pirates who cause a ruckus?
‫ربّما لأنّهم يملكون حرّاسًا شخصيّين أقوياء كفايةً‬ ‫ليتعاملوا مع القراصنة الّذين يفتعلون الجلبة؟‬
They probably do, considering the size of the city.
‫ذلك ما في الأمر غالبًا...‬ ‫باعتبار حجم هذه المدينة‬
Is that so?! Then what're we gonna do? This is bad.
‫حقًّا؟ ماذا سنفعل إذًا؟ هذا سيّئ‬
Why would it be bad? We're customers.
‫لِمَ قد يكون سيّئًا؟ نحن زبائن‬
Y-You think so?
‫أ-أهذا رأيك؟‬
Okay, then! See you later!
‫حسنًا إذًا، أراكم لاحقًا‬
Wait, Luffy and Usopp!
‫انتظرا يا لوفي و أوسوبّ‬
You two, come with me.
‫ستأتيان أنتما معي‬
Come with you where?
‫إلى أين؟‬
First, we'll take Miss Kokoro's letter of introduction and go find the man named Iceburg.
‫أوّلًا، سنأخذ الرّسالة المرجعيّة‬ ‫الّتي أعطتنا إيّاها كوكورو-سان‬
We'll ask him to facilitate the ship's repair.
‫وسنطلب منه أن يساعدنا‬ ‫على تدبير أمر إصلاح السّفينة‬
Then we have to find a place where we can cash in our gold.
‫كما يجب أن نجد مكانًا حيث‬ ‫نستطيع تصريف ذهبنا إلى مال‬
If that's it, then okay! Onward! To the City of Water!
‫فهمت... حسنًا إذًا، على أيّ حال‬ ‫لنذهب إلى مدينة الماء‬
You're forgetting the gold.
‫نسيت الذّهب‬
Hey! Some pirates are raising hell at Dock One!
‫اسمعوا، بدأ بعض القراصنة‬ ‫بافتعال الجلبة في الحوض الأول‬
What?! For real?!
‫ماذا؟ أهذا صحيح؟‬
We'd better hurry and see!
‫من الأفضل أن نذهب إلى هناك حالًا‬
I don't understand what you're talking about.
‫لا أعي ما تقول‬
A Shipyard Water Seven
‫ورشة تصليح السفن‬ ‫بووتر سيفن‬
Well, actually...
‫في الواقع...‬
Dock One
‫الحوض الأول‬
I thought about it carefully.
‫فكّرتُ في الأمر مليًّا‬
Captain Mikazuki Big Helmet Pirates Bounty: ¬36 Million
‫قبطان قراصنة: القبعة الكبيرة‬ ‫القرصان: ميكازاكي‬ ‫المكافأة: 36مليون بيري‬
I thought about it really carefully.
‫بل فكّرتُ فيه على مهل‬
While it's true that you guys repaired our ship,
‫صحيحٌ أنّكم أصلحتم سفينتنا‬
I couldn't help but notice the invoice was a bit too high.
‫لكن كيفما نظرت إلى الأمر‬ ‫فكّرتُ أنّ الرّسوم مرتفعة للغاية‬
You're interrupting our work.
‫أنتم تعرقلون عملنا‬
So... I decided not to pay—not one belly.
‫لذا قرّرت... ألّا أدفع ولا بيري واحد‬
Thanks for the flawless repairs!
‫شكرًا على الإصلاحات الممتازة‬
Plus, it's all free!
‫وفوق ذلك بالمجّان‬
Well, Kalifa, what's going on over there?
‫حسنًا يا كاليفا، ما الّذي يجري هناك؟‬
You see, Mr. Iceburg, they're customers of Dock One.
‫نعم يا أيسبرغ-سان. إنّهم زبائن الحوض الأول‬
The repairs are complete, but they refuse to pay.
‫بعد انتهاء العمل، يقولون أنّهم لن يدفعوا‬
That's sexual harassment.
‫إنّه تحرّش جنسيّ‬
Well... I suppose that is sexual harassment.
‫حسنًا... إنّه تحرّش جنسيّ‬
B-Boss!
‫ز-زعيم‬
– Boss!
‫زعيم‬
Oh, pardon me.
‫آسف‬
You son of a bitch! You should watch where you're going!
‫أيّها الحقير، راقب جيّدًا أين تذهب‬
Y-You bastards! Are you picking a fight?! Just who do you think we are?!
‫أ-أيّها الأوغاد، هل تريدون القتال؟‬ ‫من تحسبوننا؟‬
Hey, have you test-fired the cannon?
‫أخبرني، هل اختبرت إطلاق المدافع؟‬
Oh, not yet, sir.
‫ليس بعد يا سيّدي‬
Dammit! Who the hell are you guys?!
‫سحقًا، من أنتم بالضّبط؟‬
We'll remember this!
‫لن ننسى هذا‬
Galley-La Company A Shipbuilding Firm, Water Seven (Purveyors to the World Government)
‫شركة غاليلا‬ ‫منطقة صناعة السفن بووتر سيفن‬ ‫(مزود خاص لحكومة العالم)‬
The pirate way of doing things
‫أساليب القراصنة لا تنفع‬ ‫في ورشة الحرفيّين، أليس كذلك؟‬
Should we go to the exchange shop first?
‫لِمَ لا نذهب لمحلّ تصريف المال أوّلًا؟‬
Why? Let's go to the shipyard.
‫لماذا؟ لنذهب إلى حوض السفانة‬
But we can't just walk around the island with this much gold. It puts me on edge.
‫لكن لا يمكننا أن نجول الجزيرة حاملين‬ ‫هذا الكمّ من الذّهب فذلك يصيبني بالتوتر‬
Isn't it worth the same after it's exchanged?
‫تظلّ قيمته نفسها وإن صرّفناه إلى مال‬
Even so, the size of our load might attract attention, don't you think?
‫صحيح، لكنّ هذه الكومة الكبيرة‬ ‫ستجذب انتباه النّاس، أليس كذلك؟‬
What if we run into no good thieves?
‫ماذا إن صادفنا لصوصًا أشرار؟‬
But we're thieves too!
‫نحن اللّصوص‬
He's got a point. Trading it in for bills would mean we each hold on to some of it.
‫معه حقّ، إن صرّفناه إلى أموالٍ‬ ‫يمكننا حملها جميعًا‬
Hey, what's with that remark?
‫لم ترق لي طريقة كلامك‬
Is there a problem if I'm the one carrying it?
‫بدا وكأنّ حملي إيّاه هو المشكلة‬
Yeah. You might drop it or lose it somewhere.
‫نعم، قد تسقطه في مكانٍ ما أو تفقده‬
Yeah, he would. It's Luffy after all.
‫نعم، سيفعل، نحن نتحدّث عن لوفي‬
What?! Guys! Don't you trust me?!
‫ماذا؟ أنتما، ألا تثقان بي؟‬
– Nope!
‫نعم‬
Is this the only entrance to the city?
‫أهذا المدخل الوحيد للمدينة؟‬
A rental bull shop?
‫متجر تأجير بُول؟‬
What's that?
‫ما معنى ذلك؟‬
What do they rent out?
‫ما الّذي يؤجّرونه؟‬
What's a "bull"?
‫ما معنى "بُول"؟‬
Beats me. Bulldogs?
‫لا أدري، ربّما بولدغ؟‬
Can't be, right?
‫هذا مستبعد، صحيح؟‬
Excuse me! We'd like to rent some bulls!
‫المعذرة، نريد تأجير بعض البُول‬
Ask what they are first!
‫اسأل عن معناها أوّلًا‬
Welcome! Here to rent bulls, right? For how many?
‫مرحبًا، تريدون تأجير البُول، صحيح؟ كم عددكم؟‬
Three of us!
‫ثلاثة‬
What kind of bulls would you like?
‫أيّ نوع من البُول تريدون؟‬
There are three classes: yagara, rabuka, and king.
‫ثمّة ثلاثة أصناف: "ياغارا" و"رابوكا" و"كينغ"‬
Well, for the three of you, two yagaras would probably do.
‫بالنّسبة لكم أنتم الثّلاثة‬ ‫اثنان من صنف ياغارا سيكفيان‬
Okay, roast 'em nice and tasty!
‫حسنًا، أرجو أن تحمّرهما بشكلٍ جميل ولذيذ‬
Don't say weird things, you weirdo!
‫غريبة، هذه المحادثة غريبة‬
Oh? Your log pose led you here?
‫هكذا إذًا؟ تبعتم البوصلة المسجّلة إلى هنا؟‬
Yep.
‫أجل -‬ ‫هذا إنجاز كبير منكم -‬
Then you had no idea what bulls were, did you?
‫لم تكونوا تعرفون ما معنى بُول، أليس كذلك؟‬
– Right.
‫صحيح -‬ ‫حسنًا، باختصار، هذه هي بُول -‬
Yagara bulls. You'll see them all over town.
‫إنّها بُول من صنف ياغارا‬ ‫وهي سائدة في كلّ البلدة‬
In this area, there's a fish called a yagara that swims with its head out.
‫توجد في هذه المنطقة سمكة تدعى ياغارا‬ ‫وهي تسبح ورأسها خارج عن سطح الماء‬
This is the City of Water. There are more canals than walkways.
‫هذه مدينة الماء، ثمّة قنوات أكثر من الممرّات‬
The residents here see bulls as a necessary form of transportation.
‫لذا فإنّ البُول وسيلة نقل ضروريّة‬ ‫من أجل سكّان المدينة‬
Same goes for any sightseeing on the island.
‫الأمر سيان عندما تذهبون للسّياحة‬ ‫في هذه الجزيرة‬
That fish is pulling a boat?
‫تسحب السّمكة القارب؟‬
Actually, they let people ride on their backs.
‫بل تدع النّاس تركب على ظهرها بالأحرى‬
Well, it's like horseback riding or riding in a carriage on land.
‫الأمر أشبه بامتطاء الخيل أو ركوب‬ ‫عربة على اليابسة...‬
In we go!
‫حسنًا‬
You see the fish pen there? Well, try and ride on one. It's comfortable.
‫أترون حظيرة السّمك هناك؟‬ ‫جرّبوا ركوبها فذلك مريح‬
For a couple of two-passenger yagara bulls, it'll be 2,000 belly, all told.
‫ستكلّفكم 2000 بيري لاثنين بُول‬ ‫لراكبَين من صنف ياغارا‬
Wow, they're cute!
‫عجبًا، إنّها ظريفة‬
It's a fish that looks like a horse.
‫إنّها سمكة تشبه الحصان‬
You jerk! What'd you do that for?!
‫أيّها النّذل، لِمَ فعلت ذلك؟‬
Oh? He must like you. Let's get that one for you.
‫لا بدّ أنّه استلطفك، لنجهّزه من أجلك‬
Can he carry heavy stuff okay?
‫أيمكنه حمل الأغراض الثّقيلة؟‬
Their power is incredible! They're often used when moving household goods.
‫قوّتها مذهلة، حتّى أنّ بإمكانك‬ ‫استخدامها للتّرحال‬
Quite the bag, huh? Whatcha got in there?
‫تلك الحقيبة إذًا؟ ماذا يوجد بداخلها؟‬
Gold.
‫ذهب‬
Good one! Whatever it is, they can handle it.
‫أنت مضحك، أيًّا كان، ليس هناك مشكلة‬
See?
‫أرأيت؟‬
Whoa! Gimme!
‫عجبًا، أعطني القليل‬
No way!
‫مستحيل‬
This guy's awfully honest.
‫يا له من عجوز صريح...‬
And you! Don't show it off to others so casually!
‫وأنت، لا تُرِه للآخرين بهذه البساطة‬
Why's that? It's no big deal.
‫لماذا؟ لن يضرّ ذلك، صحيح؟‬
My... That was a surprise.
‫يا إلهي... يا لها من مفاجأة...‬
Well, then... It'll be a million belly for two yagara bulls.
‫حسنًا... سأحاسبكم مليونيّ بيري لِقاء‬ ‫اثنين من البُول من صنف ياغارا‬
Hey, the price went up, pops.
‫لقد رفعت الثّمن أيّها العمّ‬
Oh, right, are there any exchange shops around here?
‫بالمناسبة، أثمّة أيّ محلّات صرف في الجوار؟‬
Yeah, there are, but with that amount of gold, the shops here probably won't have enough money.
‫أجل، هنالك، لكن مع تلك الكميّة من الذّهب‬
You should go downtown on Shipyard Island.
‫عليكم الذّهاب إلى وسط المدينة‬ ‫في جزيرة السفانة‬
Downtown Shipyard Island? Where's that?
‫وسط المدينة في جزيرة السفانة؟ أين تقع؟‬
In that direction. Take this with you.
‫هنالك، خذوا هذه معكم‬
A map?! Aha!
‫خريطة؟‬
This'll be helpful! Thanks!
‫ستكون مفيدة، شكرًا‬
Pops, is the shipyard that way, too?
‫يا عمّ، هل حوض السفانة هناك أيضًا؟‬
Yeah. The world's number one shipyard!
‫نعم، الحوض الأوّل في العالم‬
Perfect! Once we get the money, we'll be real close to the shipyard.
‫هذا ممتاز، فور أن نحصل على المال‬ ‫بإمكاننا الذّهاب إليه على الفور‬
Yeah. We can finally have the Going Merry repaired!
‫نعم، بوسعنا إصلاح الغوينغ ميري أخيرًا‬
And we'll find a shipwright, too! I'm getting excited!
‫وسنجد سفان أيضًا، بدأتُ أتحمّس‬
Well, then...
‫حسنًا -...‬ ‫هل نذهب؟ -‬
Alright! Go, yagara!
‫حسنًا، هيّا بنا يا ياغارا‬
Thanks for your business! Be careful!
‫سرّني العمل معكم، توخّوا الحذر‬
Full speed to the shipyard!
‫أسرع إلى حوض السفانة‬
Yahoo!
‫مرحى‬